

ABOUT ME

Professionally Certified Architect for Adobe Experience Manager.

Associated with Infosys Limited from last 6.5 year with a total of 14.5 years IT experience. This experience spans across all the phases of software development life cycle, on Web based applications. Extensive experience on new proposal and walking through solutions.

Extensive experience on WCM concepts like Content management, Digital Asset Management, Workflow, Content replication and Content Caching. Extensive experience on Core Java and Web related technologies like J2EE Technologies.

Worked on various domains like Telecom, Retail and Manufacturing, Good exposure on Agile

Certification

Adobe Certified Architect – AEM – Jul 2020

Adobe Qualified - AEP - May 2020

Skills

AEM Sites

Adobe Exp Platform

Adobe Experience
Cloud

. . . .

Angular 9/Angular JS

Software research and development
Agile Methodology

RAVISANKAR RENGASAMY

Tirunelveli, TN, IN 627006 phone: +(91) 95679-54484 email: ravitvl83@gmail.com

Experience

Lead Consultant, Infosys Limited (2014 - Now)

Be a technical referent and contribute to build a long-term vision and strategy. Optimize IT landscape in terms of applications portfolio, integration, technologies with reusability and simplification. Define and broadcast standards, common rules and best practices in order to bring more agility to projects and teams. Design system by keeping in mind business alignment, quality of service, performance, stability and costs

- Extensive working experience on Telecom and Retail industries.
- Validated the client requirements during proposal phase and recommended best in class solutions.
- Involvement in effort estimation for the proposed solution and staffing plan.
- Participated various proposal across the globe and had detailed walk through to the solution for proposed new landscape.
- Extended the support to the technical team on crucial issues.
- Close involvement in development activities and provide solution for any type of development obstacles to make sure deliver the best in class application to client.
- Extended support for post-production hyper support

Senior Associate, Cognizant (2010 - 2014)

As Senior Associate, takes care of leading a team in a project to maintain a project's technical direction. Involved in establishing the technical vision, resolve any technical disagreements, and manage the technical quality of what their team delivers. I was co-leading a group of team members and tasked with oversight of the entire development process.

- Worked few proposals and Involvement in effort estimation for the proposed solution and staffing plan.
- Preparing requirement documents and design documents get that signed off from client.
- Involvement of development activities as in needed to deliver the application on time
- Code walk through & peer review
- Written automated Unit testing using JUnit and Jasmine framework.
- Version control management and release management
- Implementation and involved deployment process and CI/CD process.

Assistant System Engineer, TCS (2006 - 2010)

- Understand and Analyses the client requirements
- Preparing requirement documents and design documents and validate through client-side counterpart.
- Involvement of development activities as in needed to deliver the application on time
- Written automated Unit testing using JUnit.

Education

Dr Sivanthi Adithnar College of Engg (2001 - 2004)

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering